chemicalbank.com 2014-04-02

# Chemical Bank - Privacy Statement

Chemical Financial Corporation and its subsidiaries, divisions and affiliates understand that protecting the privacy of your personal and account information is critical. Whether you are a current customer or just visiting our Website, we safeguard the information you provide us at our Websites. The controls and practices we use to collect and protect this information specific to the Internet are described below. 

Click here to review a copy of our **Privacy Policy** , which describes how we safeguard, maintain, and use information we obtain about our customers in the normal course of our business. These practices also apply to the information we obtain online about our Website visitors. 

#### Protecting Online Applications

When you apply online for accounts and services, or enroll in online banking, you provide personal information that is necessary for us to process your application. To ensure that your application remains confidential, the information is maintained in a secure area on our Website. 

We, along with the outside companies with which we work, if applicable, may keep the information you provide to us, along with information we collect from outside sources, so that we can offer you accounts and services related to your financial needs. After you have submitted your application online, we recommend that you end your browser session before leaving your computer. 

#### How We Handle E-Mail

We preserve the content of your e-mail messages and our responses so that we can more efficiently handle any follow-up questions that you may have. If we think that a particular Chemical Bank account or service might apply to your situation, we may occasionally contact you at your e-mail address to inform you of potential benefits and availability. 

#### Online Surveys

Your opinions are important to us. The information you provide on surveys and promotions on our Website will be used for internal marketing purposes, including developing Website content and services that you may find helpful. 

#### Protecting Your Online Banking

We require a User ID and Password to access your accounts. If you do not provide this information, we cannot establish an online banking session for you. You can also help maintain the security of your banking information by not sharing your User ID or Password with anyone, by changing your Password regularly, and by remembering to sign off. Click here for more information on our **eBanking Security**. 

#### What Information We Collect

You can visit this site to find out about our products and services, read our financial reports, check on employment opportunities, and use our financial calculators and other services without providing any information about yourself. We do not capture any personal information without your permission. 

We do collect information about our Website usage. This includes what pages are visited, length of stay, and domain names (for example, aol.com, fast.net, etc.). This information is used to evaluate and continually improve the effectiveness of our site, and will not be disclosed to any external entity. 

#### Information We Obtain From Visitors Browsing and via Cookies

For a more effective Website, we use “cookies” as part of our interaction with your browser. A “cookie” is a commonly used small text file placed on your hard drive by our Web page server. By configuring your preferences or options in your browser, you determine if and how a cookie will be accepted. We use cookies to determine if you have previously visited our Website and for a number of administrative and marketing purposes. These cookies **_do not_** collect personally identifiable information, and we **_do not_** combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to determine who you are or your e-mail address. 

If the use of cookies is a concern to you, then please set your browser to alert you accordingly. Newer browser versions allow you to be alerted or to automatically refuse cookies. You may need to download a more current version of your web browser from your service provider in order to obtain this option.

#### Children Visiting Our Website

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) was passed to give parents increased control over what information is collected from their children online and how such information is used. The law applies to websites and services directed to, and which knowingly collects information from, children under the age of 13. There may be some pages within Chemical Bank's Website that are directed to children under the age of 13; however Chemical Bank **_does not_** knowingly collect personal information from these sites. These pages are simply provided to the child for educational purposes. For additional information on COPPA protections, please visit the Federal Trade Commission's Children's Privacy Website at [http://business.ftc.gov/privacy-and-security/children’s-privacy](http://business.ftc.gov/privacy-and-security/children%E2%80%99s-privacy). 

#### External Links

Chemical Bank is not responsible for the information practices employed by sites linked to or from our Website. In most cases, links to non-Chemical Bank Websites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of the Chemical Bank Website. 

#### Privacy Commitment to You

Trust us to keep you informed of how we protect your privacy and limit the sharing of information you provide to us - whether it's at a banking center, over the phone or through the Internet. 

#### How To Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about our privacy policies, please contact us at 800-867-9757.
